Some secrets are too terrible to reveal. Some
crimes are too unspeakable to solve.
An Amish Murder is a thriller, mystery, drama film
directed by Stephen Gyllenhaal.
The Amish farming community of Painter’s Mill, Ohio, is shattered when a series of brutal
murders leaves the town with a sense of frailty and loss of innocence.
Among the most affected by the tragedy was Kate Burkholder, a young girl who
survived the terror and, as a result, left the Amish life behind.
Fifteen years later, Kate returns to Painter’s Mill as its Chief of Police.
Certain she’s come to terms with her past, Kate’s renewed life in her hometown is shattered when a murder
investigation triggers deep-seated emotions from her childhood and exposes a dark secret that could destroy her.
Kate Burkholder, played by Neve Campbell.
John Tomasetti, played by Noam Jenkins.
Nathan Detrick, played by C. Thomas Howell.
Jacob Burkholder, played by Christian Campbell.
Lucas Holst, played by Jilon VanOver.
Glock Nichols, played by Irone Singleton.
Witness is a 1985 American neo-noir crime thriller film directed by Peter Weir.
Starring Harrison Ford, its plot focuses on a police detective protecting an Amish woman and her son, who
becomes a target after he witnesses a brutal murder in a Philadelphia railroad station.
Filmed in 1984, Witness was released theatrically by
Paramount Pictures in February 1985.
The film received positive reviews upon release and became a
sleeper hit, grossing over $117.37 million worldwide.
At the 58th Academy Awards, it earned eight nominations, including Best Picture and Best
Actor for Ford, winning Best Original Screenplay and Best Film Editing.
It was also nominated for seven BAFTA Awards, winning one for
Maurice Jarre's score, and six Golden Globe Awards.
William Kelley and Earl W.
Wallace won the Writers Guild of America Award for Best Original Screenplay and the 1986 Edgar
Award for Best Motion Picture Screenplay presented by the Mystery Writers of America.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.